I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
So that's the port town Pazzio!
Looks like there's lots of delicious foods here.
Hey!
Shouldn't you hide your face?
What's that supposed to mean?
If you've lived in the village for hundreds of years,
won't there be some folktales about your human form?
"Holo occasionally makes an appearance in the village in the form of a beautiful girl of about fifteen."
"She has long, flowing hair, the ears of a wolf, and a splendid, dark brown, white-tipped tail."
"She promises a plentiful harvest in return for keeping her appearance a secret."
Then they know exactly what you look like!
You doubted my identity, and so would others.
Only seeing my ears or tail would make them take a second glance.
You might be right.
There's no chance.
I've been long forgotten.
That's all I can ask for as far as I'm concerned.
Well, you needn't worry.
Wolf and Business Acumen
This town is everything I expected!
It's true. Those are some fine apples.
Right?
They look delicious, no?
Indeed.
Now that I think of it, I had a friend who invested in apples.
He spent half of his life savings.
If they turned out like those, he must have doubled his investment by now.
I should have done the same.
Well... that's most unfortunate...
Then again, the risk would have been high.
I would have transported them by ship.
By... ship, you say?
If you get shipwrecked you might lose your life,
but there's also huge profit to be made.
Sometimes merchants will enter a contract where they all pool some money and rent a ship, and...
What's the matter?
It's nothing.
So once they rent the ship, each merchant can load it with an amount of goods proportional to how much they've invested.
Apples...
I want... to eat... apples...
Oh, is that what you wanted?
Buy as much as you'd like with this.
Who said you could spend all of it?
You're the one who said I could buy as much as I like.
Don't you know the meaning of the word restraint?
You better earn money for your own meals.
I know you pretended not to notice.
Didn't you?
It's amusing knowing what someone else is thinking.
Those are mine!
It was my money!
I'm Holo, the wise wolf.
I can make such a petty amount in no time at all.
Oh, glad to hear it!
I was planning to use that money on tonight's room and board.
I'm amazed you ate everything.
Apples are the devil's fruit,
full of tempting sweetness as they are.
Shouldn't a wise wolf be able to conquer temptation?
Gluttony may be destructive, but that doesn't mean abstinence is constructive.
That's where we'll do business today.
The entrance may be big, but I think I saw larger buildings than this one.
That's right. It's the third-largest in this town.
But it's actually a branch store of a large trading company far to the south.
They don't have local connections, so they pay higher prices to compensate.
More importantly...
All kinds of information come in from their headquarters and other branches, right?
And the fact that they practice trade across borders means
they'll know of any fluctuations in the value of currency.
Exactly.
I'm going to casually ask about Zheren's story.
I may be able to confirm something.
Welcome to Milone Trading!
I sold wheat here three years ago.
I'd like to sell some fur today.
Yes, of course.
Thank you for using our services today.
Mr. Craft Lorentz, was it?
It's Lawrence.
I'm honored that you remembered me.
Not at all. I apologize for the mistake.
I was told that you want to sell fur today.
Correct.
Seventy pelts in all.
This is certainly excellent marten fur.
The supply for marten is scarce due to the fine harvest this year.
The farmers have been too preoccupied to hunt.
Yet, here I have a load of the finest of furs.
Seventy in all, was it?
Correct.
We've conducted business with each other
in the past, so how do you feel about this offer?
A hundred and thirty-two, huh?
In which currency?
Trenni silver coins.
You only see furs this fine once every several years... No, make that once every decade.
I'd like to direct your attention to the fact that its shine hasn't faded, despite it being transported through the rain.
It's as you say. The luster is second to none, and the coat has a good lie.
These are furs of a quality rarely seen before.
I'm hoping to keep a good relationship with your company.
As are we, I assure you.
In that case, how about a hundred and forty for the sake of developing that relationship?
Yes, that sounds...
Excuse me a moment.
I don't know the market value.
How's the offer?
It's superb.
In that case, will you accept the offer?
One hundred and forty Trenni silver pieces!
That is what you said, is it not?
Yes, a hundred and forty Trenni silver coins, indeed.
You seem to be a cut above most merchants.
Is that why you pretended not to notice?
We'd be wise to be wary of trading with you.
I-I beg your pardon. Is there something I may have overlooked?
Master, it's not polite to make sport of people.
T-That was not my aim.
I'll let you explain on my behalf.
Now, sir,
please take the fur in your hands and smell it.
Smell something, do you?
This might be... the scent of fruit, perhaps?
Indeed.
The tree branches drooped with the weight of fruit this year.
These are the furs of marten that have been scampering about in the woods until just recently.
They've been eating lavishly, which is why a sweet fragrance permeates from their bodies.
Yes, I notice the aroma.
These are furs from the finest marten.
It took two grown men to flay the hide from the body, it was so tough.
Don't be reserved. Pull it with all your strength.
Harder.
The fur is as strong as the beast itself was, and the warmth it provides is like sunshine on a spring day.
It will repel rain from dawn 'til dusk,
and don't forget the scent!
Imagine coming across a perfumed piece like this
among coats made from nose-wrinkling marten fur.
Why, 'twould sell so dear your eyes would pop out.
Now then! What price will you offer?
How about two hundred Trenni silver coins?
How does three pieces of silver per fur sound?
Two hundred and ten in all.
Well...
Master, aren't there other trading companies?
Very well. Two hundred and ten pieces it is.
You heard him, master.
Yeah...
Cheers!
Nothing beats the taste of good wine!
What's the matter? Are you not going to drink?
It's my treat.
Have you ever worked as a merchant?
What is it? Did my actions wound your pride or something?
Well, I do not quite remember when, but that idea dates from a long time ago.
A clever merchant who was passing through the village came up with it.
It wasn't something I came up with myself.
I really hadn't noticed, though.
Actually, even last night when I slept in the furs, I didn't smell any fruit.
Well, of course not. It's because of the apples I bought earlier.
In other words...
It's his own fault for being tricked!
Well, maybe not, but I'm sure he'll be impressed and glad to learn of the truth.
I suppose.
It's fruitless to be incensed after being deceived.
Being able to be impressed and learn is what makes an adult.
So, did you find the other thing you were looking for?
After a fashion.
They haven't heard any rumors about a country that's planning to renew its currency.
Well, whatever the trick with Zheren's story,
I don't mind as long as there's a profit to be made.
Here's to our reunion.
Cheers!
Being able to drink such wonderful wine must mean you sold the furs for a good price, right?
More or less.
That's great! More capital means more profit for me!
More importantly...
Yes?
In exchange for information regarding the currency that's going to be reissued,
you want a percentage of my profits.
That sums it up, correct?
Yes.
Can your information be trusted?
Well, I'm predicting it based off snippets I heard in a mining camp.
I think it's trustworthy.
However...
There are no guarantees in business.
I would have walked away if you had said it was a sure thing.
Nothing is more suspicious than a guarantee.
What percentage did you want?
Oh, right. I'd like ten Trenni pieces for the information.
Plus ten percent of your profit, sir.
That's a rather modest amount.
Well, there's nothing I can do for you in the event of a loss.
I'll take just ten percent, but if you lose everything, I'll refund the information fee and no more.
That sounds good enough to me.
Thank you very much.
In that case, can we visit the notary public tomorrow?
To our profit.
To our profit!
Cheers!
Farum silver coin!
Wrong. It's a counterfeit Marinne silver coin.
Is that not this one?
That's a later version of Bishop Radeon silver coin.
Well, you'll learn quickly once you start using them.
Let's continue once we're sober.
No, one more time!
As you wish.
I'm going to start from here. Pay close attention.
Okay.
Trenni silver coin, Philing silver coin,
Lute silver coin, counterfeit Marinne silver coin,
Farum silver coin, Bald King Ranbalt silver coin,
Mitzfing Cathedral silver coin,
counterfeit Mitzfing Cathedral silver coin,
St. Mitzfing silver coin, and last but not least...
I've had enough. I'm going to bed.
A decision befitting a wise wolf.
Why are there so many of them to begin with?
It's too confusing.
It's due to the endless cycle of countries rising and falling.
Also, rural authorities and leaders involved with the church reissue currency at will.
Add counterfeits to the mix, and, well...
Actually, Lute silver coins were originally called counterfeit Trenni silver coins, and...
Don't fall asleep on me.
I'll make good use of this information.
You have my gratitude.
Thank you very much.
I'll be on my way, sir.
Okay.
Make a killing, sir!
Stay beautiful, madam!
He was noisy right to the very end.
This is the silver coin in question, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's a credible form of currency in this area.
Credible?
There are several hundred currencies in existence, and the
amount of gold or silver often fluctuates in many of them.
Basically, the value of money is much greater than the amount of gold or silver it contains.
That extra value comes from trust.
I see.
Is there anything you've learned now that you know this is the coin?
Well...
I might not know all the details, but I have an idea.
What's the matter?
I want to eat one of those.
Those?
So, what did you realize?
Do you remember which coin this is?
Philing silver coin?
Correct.
Its silver content is extremely high,
and it's popular in the marketplace.
It rivals the Trenni coin in that respect.
It seems the strength of a country is reflected in its currency in every age.
Right. When the local market is dominated by a foreign
currency, the economy will become dependent on it.
It's no different from losing a war.
In order to defeat a rival's currency, you have to increase the purity of your own coins, right?
Yeah, which is why Zheren may not be lying about the situation.
It's true that my ears aren't completely flawless.
What? Did you think I was going to be angry?
I sure did.
I may get upset about you thinking that way, though.
Where are we going?
I happen to know a money changer.
A money changer?
A small change to a coin's purity would be impossible for a layman to detect.
Yet a big reason why coin value fluctuates is that people care about changes in purity.
People see minor changes as precursors to major ones.
That's why there's always a precursor before a big change.
You don't have to learn all of this at once.
I'll gradually explain it to you over the next month.
In other words,
when a mint decides to drastically change the purity,
they first increase it by a small fraction to gauge public reaction.
Depending on the reaction, they wait for an appropriate time to increase its value.
Y-Yeah. Something like that.
Lawrence!
Weiz!
Long time no see!
Come on.
Young lady, who might you be?
Me?
My name is Holo.
Holo! What a wonderful name.
Lawrence, have you slept with her yet?
Of course not!
So she's fair game, then?
May I have the honor?
I-I don't know...
My business with you comes first.
Do you have any recently-issued Trenni silver coins?
There's no way.
We handle it every day, but we haven't noticed anything.
Do you want to melt it down and find out?
Don't be ridiculous! There's no way we could do that.
Could I take a look?
Please, be my guest!
You're a wicked man.
Well, just watch.
I don't think it's possible to distinguish them like that, Miss Holo.
I've heard that some money changers who've worked for decades can do that,
but those are just legends.
What do you think?
I can't tell.
Oh, too bad! Too bad, indeed!
Don't worry about it.
He was interesting, wasn't he?
He's a womanizer without peer.
So, did the silver content increase or decrease?
If that was just a guess, then you've gotten much more sly.
I noticed a slight movement in your ears.
Can't let my guard down.
I was surprised you didn't say anything back there.
Well, think of it as an act of compensation.
Compensation?
You were a little jealous, weren't you?
This is in exchange.
Don't make such a worried face.
All men burn with foolish jealousy,
and women are foolish enough to take delight in it.
The world is full of fools.
Wait. What about the silver?
It was subtle, but the new coins sounded dull in comparison.
Dull?
That means that its purity has decreased.
So Zheren really was lying?
You can only make long-term profits from a depreciating currency.
If you sell your coins and buy them back after the price drops, you'll end up with more.
There's a profit to be made once the price recovers,
but six months isn't enough time.
There has to be another way for Zheren to profit.
Have you not been tricked?
Tricked?
That's right.
Do you mean I was swindled out of the ten silver coins?
In the worst-case scenario, the boy breaks even.
Even if the value of the silver coin depreciates and you face losses,
all that young man has to do is return the information fee.
But he'll receive a share of your profit, if there is any.
He's in a position to make a profit without any capital and won't incur any losses.
Oh my God.
Human beings are ingenious.
However,
is it normal for there to be a decrease in a coin's silver content?
No, normally the purity is maintained with extreme care.
A deal that hinges on the purity of this particular coin has come out of nowhere. Is that just a coincidence?
When we hunt, we occasionally climb trees.
We're able to see hidden lairs of our prey from that vantage point.
It's necessary to change your perspective in times like these.
Change my perspective?
What if the person behind this scheme wasn't that young man?
That young man's profit doesn't necessarily have to come from the people he tricked.
He could have been asked to spread news about a suspicious deal in return for a service fee.
That's it! I understand everything!
There's a way to make a profit by buying as much of a depreciating currency as you can!
Looks like something clicked.
Let's go!
Where are we going?
Milone Trading.
Next Episode: "Wolf and the Helpless Partner."